[Music]
It sounds like the carburettor.
Yes, I'm aware of that.
She's not cooperating.
Try again tomorrow.
Can you give this to Audrey for me?
Is there any message?
She'll know what it's for.
Maggie asked me to give you this.
Oh, thank you.
Aren't you going to open it?
I'll do it later.
Ingredients have been on the ground and I've a christening cake once icing.
Is Mr. Bosworth aware of these clandestine dealings?
I can assure you everything is strictly above board.
Just called in a favour, that's all.
Someone's traipsed mud all through the hallway.
Swept it twice today.
Here, let me do it.
You've got cake to make.
I might retire to my office before someone tidies me away.
I'll be working on my speech if anyone needs me.
Oh, your parents not with you?
They're just getting settled at the B&B in there.
I'll bring them over.
Oh.
You don't see me going to all this trouble for your dad, do you?
Oh, that's different.
I hardly ever see him.
I'm just the girl that dragged you away from Glasgow.
Corrupted me.
Lured me to the dark side.
I bet they were excited to see you.
They're not interested in me.
You and Jimmy, they've come to see you.
Oh, talk of his lordship.
Did you tell Siegfried he could write a speech?
He said it was part of his godparent duties.
I'll talk to him.
And say what?
Tell him to keep it brief.
It's Siegfried we're talking about.
Come in.
He's still not back from his exams.
Yes, yes.
Darragh, B-2 to 9-7.
Mr. Biggins.
How's that nanny goat doing?
Really?
We should have seen a marked improvement by now.
Yes, I understand.
I'll be with you as soon as I can.
Problem?
He's got a lumpy jaw.
He's had me up there twice already.
You'll have to go for me, I'm afraid.
Why?
Because I'm likely to end up doing a stretch in Wormwood Scrubs if I have to spend another
second in that man's company.
If it was any other time, Siegfried, but with my parents.
Well, that's a convenient excuse, don't you think?
Everything all right?
Biggins.
Has he mentioned the gates yet?
You know he's got seven gates?
Seven?
He's going after each of the deadly sins, no doubt.
He's run me ragged with his constant vacillation, but not this time.
I meant to ask, how are you getting along with the speech for the christening?
Oh, I'm rather pleased with it, actually.
And how long is it exactly?
This is the beginning of Jimmy's spiritual journey, James.
I take my role as godparent very serious.
As do I.
But I shan't be doing a speech.
And for that we'll be eternally grateful.
Right, I shall fetch my parents.
They're champing at the bit to see Jimmy.
Abandon all hope ye who enter here.
Can I help you?
Telegram for Mr Farnon.
But Mr Farnon?
Is that them?
No, you're all right.
Oh!
You want to get that carburetor seen to?
I see you still haven't got round to fixing that gate.
Helps keep undesirables out.
As opposed to keeping them in.
I think you better take me straight to your goat, Mr Biggins.
Does this mean I'll get my money back?
On account of you misdiagnosing, like?
I'm perfectly confident in my diagnosis.
It's funny how it always ends up with me having to part with my hard-earned cash.
All right.
All right, all right.
Are you absolutely sure you administered the sulfanilamide as prescribed?
Aye.
Exactly as you said.
Then we'll need to increase the dose.
Sounds expensive.
Would you get her some fresh straw, please?
She'll need somewhere comfortable to sleep.
Oh, David.
Don't worry, old thing.
Soon I'll have you grazing again.
There we are.
Oh, come and give your granny a big hug.
It's lovely to see you both.
He's gotten so big since we last saw him.
Aye, he's a bonnie wee thing.
He's a bit grisly tonight.
Teething a bit.
It's too early for that.
He'll be wanting a feed, poor mate.
If I give him any more milk, he'll burst.
Nonsense, he's a growing boy.
He's like you, son. He's got a big appetite.
Does your mummy not feed you?
A perfect timing, Mrs H.
Mr and Mrs Harriet.
I trust you had a pleasant journey?
Aye, no complaints.
Need a hand?
What time is the christening tomorrow?
The midday.
Oh, I can't wait.
Is everything all right, Audrey?
Course.
The scones are fresh out the oven.
Tea?
Yes, please.
It's lovely.
It's very tasty.
You want to hold on to this one, son?
Oh, I can't take the credit, I'm afraid.
It's all Audrey's handiwork.
The flowers are all down to Helen.
Picked them fresh for you this morning.
What's that there?
Stimulant injection.
Won't give her the boost she needs.
Nay, she just needs some iodine.
We've been through this, Mr Biggins.
Iodine is of no use to your goat.
Yeah, you and your newfangled powders.
Some kind of commission, are you?
I wouldn't be a competent veterinary surgeon
if I prescribed something as antiquated as iodine.
Expensive things, them injections.
How much is that going to cost me?
I honestly don't know.
Oh, you'll know, all right, when you get a pen in your hand.
Send me that big bill, won't you?
All right, all right.
There we are.
Right, all we can do now is pray.
You going to charge me for that as well?
Take this, and if it doesn't work, I won't charge you.
How does that sound?
Oh, I suppose.
Now, perhaps you'd be so good as to help me with the gate.
You're joking, aren't you?
Bloody thing's a death trap.
My mother swore blind by Mrs Winslow's soothing syrup.
Later proven to contain dangerous levels of morphine.
Oh.
One last kiss from Granny before we go.
He's looking tired.
Oh, don't let that face fool you.
He'll have us up till the early hours.
Routine's the key.
James used to go down like clockwork.
Not so much as a peep out of him until morning.
Don't listen to her.
If I set her lungs on him, it could wake the dead.
Why don't you come round after breakfast?
We'll take Jimmy for a walk round Derby.
I would like that.
Good night, son.
Good night.
See you tomorrow.
Night.
That wasn't so bad, was it?
Ah.
How are Mr Biggins?
Insufferable, as ever.
All I want to do is pour myself a whisky and lie in a hot bath.
Mr Farnham...
Are we still playing host to the Scottish contingent?
A telegram arrived.
It's addressed to you.
I see.
James and Ellen are putting Jimmy to bed so you won't be disturbed.
Thank you, Mrs Hall.
Good night.
He's coming home.
What is it? Is he here?
Home tomorrow.
Is that it?
Well, Tristan's never been one for detail.
When is he back?
Your guess is as good as mine.
If you're looking for hidden meaning, I wouldn't bother.
Right, I've checked the train timetable.
There's only that one connection from London he could be on today.
Right.
It's got to be a good sign if he was able to send it himself.
Yes, I suppose so.
Well, perhaps he's just got a few days' leave.
From Cairo?
Well, it's just like Tristan Shaw, because we're about to throw a party.
Well, I hope you're right.
I don't imagine you got much sleep.
It was a frightful night.
Well, try not to assume the worst.
It's easier said than done.
It was the same when he was a child.
Falling out of trees, riding his bicycle without brakes.
Never thought for his own safety.
He's resilient. Always has been.
Where are my plastic... Oh, thank you.
Would you like me to come with you?
I think it best I do this by myself.
I will never utter a crossword to that boy again if he comes home in one piece.
Oh, not today.
Not today!
Not today.
Come on!
Not now!
To be early is to be on time.
To be on time is to be late.
And to be late is unacceptable.
You drummed that into me enough times.
Aren't you going to say something?
Can I help you?
Oh, I'm sorry.
I didn't realise the surgery was closed today.
Oh, I'm sure my son can help you.
He's a partner here.
James Herriot, MRCVS.
Graduated top of his class at Glasgow University.
Oh, I don't like to interrupt him.
Oh, nonsense. He'll be glad to help.
Shall we?
Oh.
Just don't talk to them about football.
Or Mrs Winslow's soothing syrup.
Morning.
We're almost ready to go.
James.
Making friends, is he?
Oh, I'm sorry, Mr Herriot.
Your mother insisted.
It happened.
She insisted.
The animals always come first.
Isn't that right, James?
Indeed it is.
Do you mind?
I'll have to catch you up.
No, of course not.
How about we start at the Victory Garden?
Great.
You can give me some tips for my radishes.
See you later, then.
Sorry.
And who do we have here, then?
This is Lucy.
She's a fine-looking dog.
Eh?
Yes.
Well, what seems to be the problem?
She's obsessed with Emmeline.
Emmeline?
It's got to the point where she won't leave home without her.
This is what she does.
Well, let's get her inside.
See if we can't get to the bottom of it.
Oh, erm...
OK.
All right.
Is that you, Mr Farnham?
Which one were you looking for?
Get over here.
I've been setting this up since Cairo.
Everything's intact.
No bones broken.
Not a hair out of place.
Well, go on. Tell her about your promotion.
He's only been put in charge of training new veterinary recruits in Doncaster.
No, it's just lecturing. Not all the training.
You know me, Mrs H.
Never one to boast about my achievements.
Is that for me?
Just a little treat. I've been serving for you.
Oh, life doesn't get any better.
Oh, is Jim here?
I think so.
James Herriot, get out here!
James!
I tried confiscating it, but she went and took a chunk out my hand.
And that's the first time she's ever turned like that.
Well, that wouldn't do at all.
See? That's what she does.
Well, you're lucky she didn't try and nip you, too.
James Herriot, get out here!
I think...
I think what we have here is a case of overstimulation.
Is it serious?
Well, that's nothing to worry about.
While toys can be great for dogs, sometimes they can form unhealthy attachments.
So what do you suggest?
Well, I think a period of enforced separation might be in order.
Well, she won't like that at all.
Don't worry.
Annaline's just going on a little adventure.
Keep her distracted with plenty of walks.
Maybe they'll treat her, too.
Pop back in a couple of days and we'll see how she's getting on.
Yes, I will do. Thank you, Mr Herriot.
Mind it you go, Lucy.
Here you are.
What's all this I hear about Jimmy stealing my thunder?
What's all this groaning on your top lip?
So?
How are you?
Exhausted.
Never met so many hardened drinkers in all my life.
You back for good?
I'm in Doncaster three days a week until I'm redeployed.
That's still Yorkshire.
Just.
The rest of the time is my own. I'm a man of leisure.
Excellent. We could do with another pair of hands.
Last time I checked, I actually don't work for you anymore.
Yes, quite right. My mistake.
Let me grab these for you.
Yes, good. You can fill me in on what's been happening around here.
That's exactly as you left it.
With the addition of wee Jimmy, of course.
That's not good enough. I want salacious scandal. Come on.
So what did they have you doing out there?
Field support, mainly.
Making sure the animals were fit for duty.
Horses, mules, the odd camel.
The unsung heroes, eh?
It would appear we have an interloper.
That's Hamish.
With very questionable taste in bow ties.
That would be Carmody.
He's in London finishing off his final exams.
Be back in a week or two.
The Pretender to my throne.
I can't wait to meet him.
Did Siegfried not mention him in his letters?
No, he told me he'd hired a new assistant.
He neglected to tell me he was now sleeping in my bed.
Tristan, there's someone who wants to meet you.
I think he was just grateful for the distraction.
He's missed you.
We all have.
I'll leave you to it, shall I?
How was the walk?
Oh, we had a smashing time.
Fresh air's the key.
You loved having his pram pushed by his granny, didn't you?
Eh?
And the Victory Garden.
Oh, lovely.
Yes, I wonder how she found the time.
With wee Jimmy to care for.
Where were you?
I got caught up in something here.
I don't believe it.
This isn't a mirage, Helen.
It really is me.
Older, wiser, more handsome than ever.
Mr and Mrs Heriot.
You're looking younger by the day.
It's lovely to see you.
Hi.
Back where you belong.
And this is young Jimmy, I take it?
He's excited to meet his Uncle Tristan.
May I?
Hello.
Are you waiting for him to reply?
No.
I'm just trying to work out who he looks like.
Well, he's a handsome young thing.
So I'm guessing he's got his mother's genes.
Sorry to break up the party, but we're due at the church soon.
Is it that time already?
I need to get Jimmy his gown.
Oh, don't you worry.
We'll keep the becker talking.
Are you sure you're not too tired from your journey?
What?
Miss you, renounce the devil?
Not a chance.
Sacred occasion, Tristan.
That doesn't mean we can't have a bit of fun.
Shall we?
Let's go.
Dearly beloved, you have brought the child here today to be baptised.
That our Lord Jesus Christ would receive him and release him from sin.
To sanctify him with the Holy Ghost.
To give him the kingdom of heaven and everlasting life.
Now, can I please ask the family to gather at the font?
Did they throw you out?
It was quite the scandal.
How many times did you fall in love?
Oh, just once, Layla.
My Arabian camel.
She was exotic, feisty.
She did have a tendency to get the hamper.
Tristan.
Sorry, Vicar.
Could I ask the godparents to step forward?
Do thou, in the name of this child, renounce the devil?
Do thou, in the name of this child, renounce the devil and all of his works?
I renounce them all.
Will you then obediently keep God's holy will and the commandments
and walk in the same all the days of thy life?
I will, by God's help.
Would one of the godparents take Jimmy?
Layla.
Almighty ever-living God,
sanctify this water to the mystical washing away of sin.
Grant that this child receives the fullness of thy grace.
Through Jesus Christ, our Lord. Amen.
Amen.
Would you please name the child?
James Alexander.
Right, young man?
It's your turn.
Is he good with water?
Only if there's ducks.
I baptize thee in the name of the Father,
the Son,
and the Holy Ghost.
Amen.
I thought that went rather well.
Mrs. Hall will need some time to prepare the lunch,
and then we can move on to the speeches.
There's more than one?
I was talking figuratively, James.
Hang on, hang on.
Isn't it customary to wet the baby's head?
That's the night the baby's born, not just after the christening.
Well, I missed the birth on account of me fighting for my country.
I don't think it's appropriate, not today.
Don't you want to buy your brother a pint?
You've been away fighting a war.
Of course I do, but there's a schedule to stick to.
Another hour ain't going to work.
I'll have lunch ready for when you get back.
Right, that's settled then.
James, you coming for one?
One.
Mum, I want to get back to the house.
Another time.
You go with Tristan.
I'll take your mum back.
That's very kind of you.
Are you sure?
Just don't let him lead you astray.
I'll be an hour tops.
I'm so sorry, Helen.
I'm sure Tristan didn't mean to commandeer your day.
Right, let's make a start on this spread.
Actually, I'd rather go with James and Tristan.
And when we're still an adult, I can do what I like.
I don't like it. It shouldn't be in a bar.
Absolutely not.
Tris, what are you having?
I'll put your money away, James.
This round's on me.
Five pints of your finest, please, barmaid.
Oh, make that six.
Look at what the cat's dragged in.
Egypt's finest export.
I see the war's done nothing to dampen your spirit.
How have you been?
Surviving.
Just about.
Any word from Arthur?
They've got him stationed out in North Africa.
Libya, I think it was.
Well, it's a shame our paths never crossed.
We could have pined together over...
...Darabee.
Enemy sighted at three o'clock.
I'm afraid so.
Enemy...
Enemy sighted at three o'clock.
Oh, is that Biggins?
He's like the Grim Reaper.
Lurking round every corner.
Look, you've only got yourselves to blame.
You should have stopped taking that old rascal's business years ago.
Well, then.
Where is it you were stationed? Cairo, was it?
Indeed.
Yeah, it was a scene of much heartbreak for many of us.
Aye.
Lost a lot of men.
I'm talking about the women.
It can't have been easy, though.
Working in that heat.
That was exhausting.
Yeah, deadly at times.
How did you get through it?
The Cairo cafe, mainly.
Sometimes the turf club, depending on, you know, my mood.
Come on, you must have seen some hardship out there.
You know me, James.
Never want to let a little bloodshed get me down.
Well, that'll be six shillings.
Exactly.
Tristan?
Would you mind? I've left my wallet in my other trousers.
There you go.
Can I help at all?
Oh, no, you're all right.
We're nearly done now.
Well, that was a lovely service.
Oh, thank you.
Jimmy enjoyed it.
Do you want a brew?
Oh, no, no, you carry on as you are.
I'm happy just sitting here.
So this is where you eat all your meals?
Most of the time, yes.
That makes sense.
You don't want to stay cooked up in that cramped attic.
Oh, Jimmy's awake.
Oh, shall I get him?
Don't worry, I'll go.
Hello.
Yes.
Where should I put these?
Oh, on the table's fine.
Did you hear that?
Sounded like scratching.
Did you?
Oh, what are you doing here on your own?
I need some help here.
Oh.
Clawed at the door, she was.
Her name was Rosa.
She was a Canadian, stationed at the field hospital.
She were a looker.
We're talking Betty Grable here.
Legs that went on mine.
What happened to her?
Her heart laid with another.
Royal engineer from Cleethorpes.
God's sake, it's hardly a farewell to arms.
Just out of interest, did you do any work over there, Tristan?
Excellent question.
I did my fair share.
There was a capture of Sidi Barani, for one.
Why?
Big lad, was he?
It's on the Egypt-Libya border.
You were part of that campaign.
A small part, yes.
How exactly?
Because from what I can gather,
you spent your time drifting from one bar to another.
A lot's changed since your day, Siegfried.
Is that so?
You lot relied on tin hats and blind faith.
Nowadays, we prefer a more strategic approach.
Isn't that right, James?
Absolutely.
I think you'll find...
Do you know what? Forget it.
If you'll excuse me, I need some air.
Mr Biggins!
How's your goat? Any improvement?
Well, she's got worse, if anything.
I'll be wanting my money back on that prescription of yours.
Are you sure you're administering it correctly?
You're saying I can't make out instructions, is that it?
I'm saying no such thing.
I just don't understand why it hasn't taken effect.
Because the stuff you gave me is bloody useless.
You hear this, Alderson?
Victory's only been after trying to power me off with some fake powders.
Fake powder sounds like my domain.
How can I be of assistance?
Everything's under control.
He's just slandered your name in a pub full of paying customers.
That's Peg, I feel sorry for.
Treating her like some kind of experiment.
Right, that's it.
I insist on having another look.
Hang on a minute.
There's no trouble at all.
Wait for me.
What are you doing?
I'm coming with you.
There's really no need.
What are you talking about?
He's besmirching our good name.
James, will you pass on my apologies to Mrs. Hall?
Aye, of course.
You know, I encountered my fair share of goats in Egypt.
There's a particular knack with them.
I could give you some points as...
You know, I encountered my fair share of goats in Egypt.
There's a particular knack with them.
I could give you some points as...
Keep still.
Why would she come back here?
I don't know, but she's after something.
What is it?
What are you looking for, eh?
Is she after food?
I don't think so.
What?
It's not this, is it?
All this for a tie?
What are the symptoms?
Difficulty eating, salivating.
Come on, let's have a little look at you.
Ah, yes. She has nodules in the jaw, swelling around the neck and face.
Has to be actinomycosis.
In English?
Lumpy jaw, Mr. Biggins.
Which was my original diagnosis.
Can I see the prescription I gave you yesterday?
What for?
Because I can't believe you've administered it correctly.
Are you calling me a liar?
He was merely asking for confirmation, Mr. Biggins.
All I want is my money back from those dodgy powders of yours.
You should count yourself lucky we're not in Egypt.
They'd have just slapped on some iodine and hoped for the best.
No, no, thankfully we're a little more advanced in our way of thinking here.
You bare-faced cheek of a...
Sorry?
You, making out I don't know what's best for me animals.
All I'm saying is that...
I think you've said more than enough already, don't you?
Could my brother use your stove to make up a warm compress?
It might help reduce Peg's swelling.
Ah, Aspall.
Now, where were we?
You slander in my good name.
Yes.
BIRDS CHIRP
James told me stories about your dog.
He's done, isn't he? Aye.
James tears up every time he's mentioned.
You know, he still waits at the door for James to come home.
Oh.
We both do.
She's treating that toy like it's a baby.
Oh, I remember that feeling.
You never want to let go.
Gives me a pain in my chest just thinking about it.
You're doing a wonderful job.
You know that, don't you?
What is it?
I think her tits might be swollen.
Ellen!
Rene!
What's Lucy doing here?
We found her scratching at the door.
Turns out she left someone behind.
Emmeline?
I think it's more than just a toy to her, James.
I think it might be a phantom pregnancy.
BIRDS CHIRP
You sly old fox.
Ellen's right.
Her mammary glands are definitely swollen.
So it is a phantom pregnancy.
Oh, I'm impressed.
They get the idea they're going to have pups after they've been in season.
Some even get a swelling in the abdomen.
Oh, she just wanted to be with her pup.
I can't believe you tried to take her baby, James.
She was being aggressive.
I did it for her own safety.
You locked her away in a drawer.
Maybe we shouldn't be too hard on the boy.
Perhaps it's something only a mother can understand.
BIRDS CHIRP
Where's Biggins?
Tormenting one of his farmhands, probably.
What happened to the compress?
I got a little distracted.
I can't believe he lied to my face.
Just to worm his way out of pain.
Maybe it's time we give him a taste for his own medicine.
Don't you think?
Oh.
Well, I hope you're not charging me by the hour, Father.
I was just saying to my brother, Mr Biggins, all this talk of Egypt.
It's got me thinking.
Do you mind if I check one more thing?
Oh, I suppose.
Right, come here. Let's have a look at you.
Yeah.
Just as I suspected.
Nile fever.
Oh.
Nile what?
Fever.
It's mainly prevalent in North Africa. I'm fairly certain your goat has it.
Well, how?
She's never been to Africa.
Spittle.
Yes.
Come again?
On the back of her postage stamp, no doubt.
You're winding me up.
Your son's in the army, isn't he?
Yeah, Royal Tank Regiment.
Oh, well, that explains it. It's airborne, you see.
Airborne.
I'm meant to believe that African Spittle is killing Margot.
No, no, no. She's not dying. Far from it.
A simple injection should sort her out.
I must say, it's a good job you've been using our medicine.
How do you mean?
Well, if not, the injection could cause serious, serious consequences for the animal.
You mean it could kill her?
Within seconds.
But you've nothing to worry about. She's had the sulfanilamide.
Oh, no, no. There's been a misunderstanding.
What sort of misunderstanding?
I just...
I just don't think she's been getting enough of the stuff.
Maybe I'll need to increase the dosage.
I always find it easier to administer if you take it out of the packet.
Are you sure you've got everything?
Anyone would think he was trying to get rid of us.
Did Mrs. Hall give you some cake?
Enough to see us through till winter.
One last cuddle for your granny before we go.
Goodbye, sir.
Quite soon?
Every Sunday without fail.
Why do I feel like I'm being ganged up on here?
Get used to it.
You two seem to be getting on famously now.
Maybe we could invite them to stay for the summer.
Let's not get carried away.
James? Helen?
Looks like the party's over.
I never got to do my speech.
Then do it for me now.
Don't be ridiculous.
I'm being serious.
I want to hear it.
Perhaps an abridged version?
Music to my ears.
I thought I'd start by talking about the Emperor Penguin.
That might be where you lose your audience.
And how fatherhood takes many forms.
But however they manifest,
all fathers, God, surrogate or otherwise,
share one common desire.
To help those under their care become the best version of themselves.
Job done.
The trouble is, when they start to forge their own path,
and you realise the roles have somehow reversed.
I don't know what to do.
The roles have somehow reversed.
You find yourself needing them.
Far more than they ever needed you.
And then I thought I'd end on a flourish with a particularly person in quote from Aristotle.
Why do you always have to go back to the Greeks?
I'm sorry if my terms of reference are too highbrow for you.
I just think it'd be nice if you chose a book we'd all read.
Like what, Tristan? The Dandy?
The Greeks built the foundations of Western civilisation?
A first class education and this is what you come out with?
It beggars belief, it really does.
I'm a student of life, not the classroom.
It's nice to see those two getting on so well.
Isn't it just?